Guide to the African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania Digital Archive AACCWP
ULS Archives & Special Collections
African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania Digital Archive
1999-2017
ULS Archives & Special Collections
African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania
AACCWP
928 items
The mission of the African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania (the Chamber) is to continuously improve business and professional opportunities for African American Business owners and professionals. Guided by the core values of [promoting] equity in opportunity, economic advancement, self-sufficiency and entrepreneurial excellence, we seek to advance economic parity for the African American Business community by insuring full participation in public and private sectors throughout the region. The material available in this online collection documents some of the history of the AACCWP through past announcements on programs and events.
Scope and Content Notes
The material documents communication efforts and planned events carried out by the African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania.
History
The African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania (AACCWP) was chartered on March 8,1994 as a Charitable Trust 501(c)(6) by a volunteer group of local businessmen who immediately began recruiting business and corporate members to join the new organization. After three years of successful creation of the base, the organization needed a central location from which to offer access to resources and information. The AACCWP began to look for office space and conducted a formal nationwide search for an Executive Director. With the help of the Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce and the Pittsburgh Regional Alliance, the AACCWP opened its office in the Regional Enterprise Tower in late September 1998 and hired its first Executive Director, Doris Carson Williams, now President and CEO.
The Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce agreed to serve as fiscal agent pending completion of requisite corporate status. The 501(c)(3) corporate status for the African American Chamber Foundation was awarded on March 15, 2000 providing the tax incentive for financial participation of mainstream corporations. It is a full service organization, offering business training, technical assistance, and business tools to strengthen the business acumen of African American and other minority firms. The membership grew from under 50 members in 1998 to its current level of over 500 small business owners and professionals, and over 35 corporate sponsors. It is now ranked the 11th largest Chamber in the Ten County region. In October 2012, the AACCWP relocated its offices to its current home in the Koppers Building, Downtown.
African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania
- Communications, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This group of material contains the Chamber's correspondence that communicates monthly, annual, and ongoing information to the membership and the general public of past events.
  - Annual Reports, 1.
    Each year the Chamber produces an Annual Report that captures highlights of the previous fiscal year's performance, Membership Benefits, the annual audit report, and recognition of our Corporate Sponsors and Special Funding Partners.
    - 2009 Annual Report
    - 2010 Annual Report
    - 2011 Annual Report
    - 2012 Annual Report
    - 2013 Annual Report
    - 2014 Annual Report
    - 2015 Annual Report
    - 2016 Annual Report
  - Newsletters, 2.
    Starting initially as a quarterly publication, members requested receiving the Chamber newsletter every month to keep informed of upcoming events, corporate activities and programs offered that benefit African American and other minority and small businesses owners. The newsletter is sent electronically to the general membership and mailed to all Corporate Sponsors and Presidential Roundtable Members.
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 1999
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 1999
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 1999
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 1999
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2000
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2000
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2001
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2002
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2003
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2004
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2005
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2006
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2007
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2008
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2009
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2010
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2011
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2012
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2013
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2014
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2015
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2016
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, Febraury 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2017
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2018
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, October 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, November 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, December 2019
    - Chamber Newsletter, January 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, February 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, March 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, April 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, May 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, June 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, July 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, August 2020
    - Chamber Newsletter, September 2020
  - Newspaper & Magazine Articles/Media Clippings, 3.
    This group of material contains the Chamber's collection of written publications and magazine articles in which the organization and its staff are recognized.
    - African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania - GPCC, 1999
    - African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania - Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce, 1999
    - Third Renaissance Inclusion - NPC, January 1999
    - New Rules Increase Access to SBA Loan Capital, February 1999
    - Renaissance woman - Prospects, February 1999
    - Promotion to President of the Western Pennsylvania Black Chamber of Commerce - NPC, June 1999
    - Study-Lack of Blacks, Women on Boards has Economic Impact - NPC, July 1999
    - Business Catalyst - PC, September 1999
    - Energized NPC, October 1999
    - Fifth Forbes and a Fork in the Road - PG, October 1999
    - 50,000 Given to Attract More Blacks to Trade Unions, December 1999
    - Taking an African American view of 2000 - TR, January 2000
    - Local Business Pursuits Paying Off, February 2000
    - Dickerson Chamber Pivitol to One Economy - NPC, May 2015
    - Guest Speaker Ralph Dickerson Jr. - PC, May 2000
    - Carson Williams Named to the Board - PC, January 2001
    - Program Instills Self-help Strengthens Families - NPC, January 2001
    - Diversity Still a Minority for Corporations - TR, February 2001
    - Census Shows Changing Racial Makeup of County, March 2001
    - Political Action - NPC, March 2001
    - New Commission to Make Rules for Minority Firm Contracts - PG, April 2001
    - Chamber Chairman Rallies Minority Business Owners - TR, May 2001
    - NAACP Leader Pushes Environment of Change - TR, May 2001
    - Thompson to Chamber-School District Open for Business - PC, June 2001
    - Growing the Group - PPG, July 2001
    - Effectively Using the Media - NPC, August 2001
    - Minority Chambers Unite to Promote More Access to Energy Trading Plan - NPC, November 2011
    - Opening Energy Door to Minorities - NPC, November 2001
    - Chamber Luncheon Celebrates America - NPC, December 2001
    - Deep Impact - NPC, December 2001
    - Full house packs District 9 forum - NPC, February 2002
    - Getting Down to Business NPC, February 2002
    - Rendell Casey Spar on Issues, Records - PG, April 2002
    - African American Chamber's Business Luncheon - NPC, May 2002
    - Mon-Fayette Expressway meeting - PC, May 2002
    - Chamber thanks Coyne for service - NPC, June 2002
    - Mon Valley NAACP to Celebrate 42 years - NPC, August 2002
    - Who Belongs to the Rivers Club - PBT, September 2002
    - Ferguson to Address Chamber - NPC, October 2002
    - Power Breakfast speaker - PC, October 2002
    - Ferguson Says Fed Remains Vigilant Against Credit Bias - NPC, November 2002
    - Fisher Tells Chamber He will Champion Small Business - NPC, Novmeber 2002
    - Taking Care of Business - NPC, December 2002
    - 25 Largest Pittsburgh Area Chambers of Commerce - PBT, March 2003
    - Candidates Dislike Idea of Appointed Board-PPG, April 2003
    - Chamber Speaker - PC, May 2003
    - Payne Believes Small Market Teams Can Thrive - PT, May 2003
    - The Economics of Baseball - NPC, May 2003
    - Roddey, Onorato Spar Over Economic Development Issues - PPG, September 2003
    - Concerns Expressed at Hearing - NPC, October 2003
    - Official Says State will Increase use of Minority Women Owned Businesses - PG, October 2003
    - Official Says State will Increase Use of Minority, Women-owned Firms - PG, October 2003
    - Chamber to Kick off Business Institute - NPC, December 2003
    - United Way, Chambers Group Partner to Start Business Briefcase - PBT, December 2003
    - Rendell Backs City Oversight Board - TR, January 2004
    - 25 Largest Pittsburgh Area Chambers of Commerce - PBT, March 2004
    - African American Chamber Changing of the Guard - Renaissance News, May 2004
    - Economy and Equality Among Specter's Priorities - PC, May 2004
    - Jobs the Main Issue, Specter Says - PPG, May 2004
    - Financial Barriers; Report Identifies Obstacles Minorities Encounter - NPC, July 2004
    - Stimulating the Economy - NPC, July 2004
    - Ask the Expert October is Legal Month - Developing & Strengthening Your Business Plan - PC, September 2004
    - Ask the Expert September is Credit and Lending Month - NPC, September 2004
    - Engines of Growth - NPC, September 2004
    - Ask the Expert November is Credit and Lending Month - NPC, October 2004
    - Usher to be Honored at Power Breakfast - NPC, October 2004
    - Black Chamber Hires New Membership, Program Director - NPC, October 2004
    - Developing and Strengthening Your Business Plan - NPC, October 2004
    - Lipton Delivers Challenging Address at Business Luncheon - NPC, December 2004
    - Ask the Expert January is Information Technology Month - NPC, January 2005
    - Onorato Shares Vision for Region, Accomplishments - NPC, January 2005
    - Fourth Annual Ice Skating Party - People, February 2005
    - Advocating for Women and Minorities PBT, February 2005
    - Ask the Expert February is Tax Month, February 2005
    - 25 Largest Pittsburgh Area Chambers of Commerce - PBT, March 2005
    - Ask the Expert March is marketing Month, March 2005
    - Ask the Expert April is Media Month, April 2005
    - Mayoral candidates Display Business Savvy - Metro, April 2005
    - Mayoral Candidates Display Business Savvy and Candidates Square off on Police and Business Issues- PC, April 2005
    - Mayoral Hopefuls Debate Police Review Board - PG, April 2005
    - Self Inflicted Wound - NPC, April 2005
    - 6th Annual Meeting - NPC, May 2005
    - Apprentice Runner up Speaks on Business Deals, May 2005
    - Nobody's Apprentice ...Kwame Jackson Speaks at Chamber- NPC, May 2005
    - Southwest Execs say Customer Service Key to Success for Airline - PPG, May 2005
    - African American Chamber Power Breakfast Scene - NPC, June 2005
    - Groups Urge Kill School Board Deal - PC, June 2005
    - Businesses, Community Groups Force 30 Day Delay on School Contract Plan - NPC, July 2005
    - Residents say Schools Labor Proposal Discriminates Against Minority Firms - PG, July 2005
    - Workshop Targets Minority Business - NPC, July 2005
    - Ask the Expert - Sept is Marketing Month - PPG, September 2005
    - Ask the Expert - September is Marketing Month - PT, September 2005
    - Ask the Expert- September is Marketing Month - PPG, September 2005
    - Ask the Expert - October is Credit and Lending Month - NPC, October 2005
    - Ask the Expert November is Information Technology Month - NPC
    - Chamber Luncheon Marks High Hopes for Procurement - NPC, December 2005
    - 12 More Business Sought for Minorities - TR, December 2005
    - 25 Largest Pittsburgh Area Chambers of Commerce - PBT, March 2006
    - Ask the Expert March is Legal Month - PG, March 2006
    - Black Business Owners on Rise - PPG, April 2006
    - New Board Members, Chair, Tributes Announced at Chamber Annual Meeting - NPC, May 2006
    - U.S. Steel Looks to Diversify - PTR, May 2006
    - Forum Gives Busineses Pointers on Using Media Effectively - NPC, July 2006
    - PennDOT Outlines Minority Contracting Gains for Chamber - NPC
    - Ask the Expert Credit Program - NPC, September 2006
    - Revamped City Council Faces African American Chamber - NPC, September 2006
    - Revamped City Council Faces African American Chamber- NPC, September 2006
    - RMU President Pledges Continued Emphasis on Diversity - NPC, October 2006
    - Ask the Expert - Accessing Capital Markets in the Public Sector, November 2006
    - Largest Pittsburgh Area Minority Owned Companies - PBT, February 2007
    - Onorato says county business climate - shovel ready - NPC, March 2007
    - CCAC Implements Contracting Diversity Plans - NPC, April 2007
    - Chamber Holds Three Part Televised Forum - NPC, April 2007
    - Meakem to be Guest Speaker at Chamber Annual Meet - NPC, May 2007
    - EEO Commissioner Updates Chamber - NPC, June 2007
    - Meakem Issues Unexpected Challenge at Chamber Luncheon - PC, June 2007
    - Procope Receives Minority Business Legacy - NPC, July 2007
    - A Unique Networking Event- The Chamber and Chihuly - NPC, August 2007
    - Bizcamp Grooms Future Entrepreneurs - PC, August 2007
    - 25 Largest Pittsburgh Area Chambers of Commerce - PBT, September 2007
    - Black Meetings & Tourism - The Authority of African American Conventions, Incentives & Leisure Travel, October 2007
    - African American Chamber of Commerce Luncheon - PG, December 2007
    - Chamber Speaker Greeted with Standing Ovation - NPC, December 2007
    - Book of lists- PBT, 2008
    - Celebrate Culture - Valley News Dispatch, February 2008
    - Hill Gives Frank Truth and Reconciliation Speech - PC, May 2008
    - Hill to Provide Insight During Chamber's Annual Meet-PC, May 2008
    - Bland Provides a Path for Regional Transit - NPC, June 2008
    - City, County Merger Could Benefit Both - NPC, July 2008
    - Key Updates Garfield Heights Progress at Chamber Breakfast - NPC, July 2008
    - African American Chamber of Commerce of Western Pennsylvania - Whirl Magazine, August 2008
    - Mayor Shares Encouraging Future for Pittsburgh - NPC, October 2008
    - A Decade of Success - NPC, November 2008
    - Business Opportunities Beyond Southwestern Pennsylvania - NPC, February 2009
    - Groups Hope Obama Phenomenon Spurs Recruits - TTM, February 2009
    - Dr. Ken Melani and Board President Doris Carson Williams - PPG, May 2009
    - A Golden Opportunity Organizers say Summit is an International Showcase for City - PC, September 2009
    - Burns Promotes Regionalism - NPC, October 2009
    - BNY Mellon 200 Short of Local Jobs Goal - PTR, December 2009
    - BNY Mellon Chair Kelly says Outlook for Economy Positive - NPC, December 2009
    - Largest Pittsburgh Area Chambers of Commerce - BT, 2010
    - McElhatton's Unique Business Model Put Your People First - NPC, March 2010
    - What Makes a New Small Business a Successful Business Smallhomebusiness.suite101.com, June 2010
    - FedEx Kicks off Chamber Power Breakfast Season - NPC, September 2010
    - iGate Chief at Chamber Breakfast - NPC, October 2010
    - Chamber Speaker Says America Needs More Scientists - PC, December 2010
    - Laxness CEO Promotes Diversity Efforts - NPC, January 2011
    - Chamber Talks Shale - NPC, February 2011
    - LanePrepare Students for Jobs - NPC, March 2011
    - Chamber Luncheon Speaker More Black Engagement Needed - NPC, May 2011
    - Workshop Aims to Help Businesses- PG, May 2011
    - African American Chamber Fratures Diabetes Workshop Series - NPC, June 2011
    - Five Simple Screenings to get on Path to Healthy Life - NPC, June 2011
    - Fontana Talks Funding Cuts at Chamber Breakfast - NPC, July 2011
    - African American Chamber Hosts Diabetes Workshop - NPC, July 2011
    - Pinnacle Financial at Chamber Breakfast - NPC, September 2011
    - Museum Director Keynotes Chamber Luncheon - NPC, December 2011